Guide to the Progressive Cities and Neighborhood Planning 1969-2005 Collection, 1969-2005
Progressive Cities and Neighborhood Planning 1969-2005 Collection, 1969-2005
- Series V. Cleveland, Ohio
  - Chronology and List of Cleveland Industrial Sector (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Chronological List of Cleveland Manufacturers 200 Employees and Over. (Box 12, Folder 15)
      Handwritten Notes. 10 pages.
    - Headquarters Cleveland. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Directions to Complete the Study on Industrial Movement in Cleveland Since 1939. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - The Baking of the Cleveland Regional Doughnut. (Box 12, Folder 15)
      2 copies. Photocopy. 2 pages.
  - Public Interest Bibliography (Box 12, Folder 16)
    Documents, 2 Copies, 5 pages
  - Catholic Community Action (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Harry Fagan Interview., Dec. 14, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Empowerment: Skills for Parish Social Action. (Box 12, Folder 17)
      Original Publication. 64 pages. -- Author: Fagan, Harry.
    - Note From Harry Fagan to Pierre Clavel. (Box 12, Folder 17)
      Original. 1 page. -- Author: Fagan, Harry.
    - Commission on Catholic Community Action, Diocese of Cleveland. Action for a Change. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Planning Commission Documents (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Cleveland Planning Commission. Impact of New Construction on the Market for Existing Downtown Office Space: Implications for the City's Revenue Base., June 1, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Cleveland Planning Commission, Special General Plan Report. Economic Feasibility Analysis: Industrial Redevelopment of National Screw and Perfection Stove Property., Mar. 1, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Cleveland City Planning Commission, 1976 Annual Report. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Cleveland City Planning Commission. 1972-1973 Annual Report. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - The Illuminating Company, a Radical Cleveland Research Group. The Cleveland Papers. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    Original Publication. 88 pages.
  - The Cleveland Foundation (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - The Cleveland Foundation. 1977 Annual Report., May 30, 1905 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      Original Publication. 64 pages.
    - The Cleveland Foundation. Quarterly., Spring 1977 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Rebuilding the Confidence of the Rider, The Plain Dealer., Aug. 21, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman.
    - Mass Transit: A Case Study. (Box 12, Folder 21)
      Photocopy. 10 pages. -- Author: Cogger, Janice.
  - Central City Plans of the 1980s for the Downtowns of the 1990s., Apr. 22, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    Photocopy. 59 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman and Dennis Keating.
  - The Impact of Community Development Revenue Sharing, Apr. 14, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    Photocopy. 8 Pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman and John Linner.
  - "A Retrospective View of Equity Planning: Cleveland 1969-1979." APA Journal. Pp. 163-74., Spring 1982
    Photocopy. 11 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman.
    - Draft of Krumholtz Article. (Box 12, Folder 24)
      2 copies. Photocopy. 25 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman.
  - Working the Advocacy-Equity Side of Street / Cleveland v NOACA., Oct. 11, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    Photocopy. 7 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman.
    - Cleveland v. NOACA, Detroit, MI., Apr. 17, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 25)
      Photocopy. 15 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman.
  - Krumholz/CPC. City Planning Articles (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - The Man Behind the City Planning Commission., Feb. 1, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      2 copies. Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Bartimole, Roldo.
    - "Calls Planner Anti-Enterprise." Cleveland Plain Dealer., June 1, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Green, Richard.
    - "Cleveland is Alive but not too Well.", Nov. 4, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Judis, John.
    - "Krumholz among most vigorous dissenters: U.S. Neighborhoods Report Criticize..." Plain Dealer., Apr. 16, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Anderzejewski, Thomas.
    - "City Planners Must Take Stand." Plain Dealer., Mar. 7, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Sabath, Donald and Roldo Bartimole.
    - "Planning Board in Power Vacuum." Plain Dealer., Feb. 27, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - "Planners Last to Hear of Plans." Plain Dealer., Feb. 28, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - "Three are Added: City Expands Its Planning Staff." Plain Dealer., Jan. 23, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Sabath, Donald.
    - "City Unveils 'New Town' Plans." Plain Dealer., Nov. 20, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - "Population Loss May Help City, Planners Say." Plain Dealer., June 29, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Murphy, John.
    - "City Planning: Little Progress Under New Charter.", May 18, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Handwritten Notes. (Box 12, Folder 26)
      Handwritten Notes. 4 pages.
  - Areawide Housing Policy: A View From The Trenches., Mar. 23, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    Photocopy. 18 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman.
  - Cleveland's Financial Crisis., Apr. 11, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    Photocopy. 19 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman.
  - Under Two Flags..., Talk at Trinity College, 1972., May 25, 1905 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    Photocopy. 29 pages. -- Author: Bonner, Ernie.
  - Personal Letter on Implementation of 1975 Policy Planning Report from Robert Brown, Nov. 9, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    Document, Copy, 6 Pages -- Author: Brown, Robert
  - The Cleveland Beacon (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - The Cleveland Beacon, 1:3., Apr. 1, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      2 copies. Original Publication. 16 pages.
    - The Cleveland Beacon, 1:4., May 1, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      3 copies. Original Publication. 16 pages.
    - The Cleveland Beacon, 1:5., June 1, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      4 copies. Original Publication. 16 pages.
  - DRAFT - Citywide Plan-Cleveland, Overview Chapter, Land Use Changes. (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Summary of Proposed Land Use Changes. (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Civic Vision: Citywide Plan and Downtown Plan., Summer 1986-Fall 1988 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Community Development News., Autumn 1988 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Community Development News., Winter 1989 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Pierre's Cleveland Chapter (Box 12, Folder 35)
    Photocopy. 56 pages. -- Author: Clavel, Pierre
  - Cleveland Development Policies and Goals. (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - The Cleveland Economy in Transition - Implications for the Future. Report to Study Participants, Regional Development Program, Cleveland State., July 1, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    Photocopy. 45 pages.
  - Greater Cleveland Growth Association (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Greater Cleveland Growth Association. Business Development Objectives for Greater Cleveland., Apr. 6, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Greater Cleveland Growth Association. Annual Report., May 31, 1905 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Greater Cleveland Growth Association - Research Department. Survey of Greater Cleveland Growth Association., July 1, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Clevelander, 8:3., Mar. 1, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 38)
      Original Publication. 14 pages.
    - Proceeds and Summaries of the Greater Cleveland Growth Association Strategic Planning Conference., Nov. 3-4, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 38)
      Original Publication. 36 pages.
  - The Population of Young Adults in Cuyahoga County, 1960-1990. Expected Changes and Implications. The Institute of Urban Studies, Cleveland State University., July 28, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    Original Publication. 57 pages. -- Author: Weld, Eric Jr.
  - Corporate Control vs. Populism: A Comparative Study of Five Cleveland Mayors. (Box 12, Folder 40)
    Photocopy. 39 Pages. -- Author: Coleman, Cynthia.
  - "The Metropolis and the Central City: Can One Government Unite Them?" Urban Affairs Quarterly, 8:4, pp 395-422., June 1, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    Author: Frisken, Francis.
  - Kucinich Articles (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Written for Seven Days, Document of unknown origin and authorship. (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - "Kucinich Defines 'Urban Populism'." The Cleveland Press., Oct. 3, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - "The Moving Target: The Mayor Who Said No - Is Dennis Kucinich As Mad As They Say?" Voice., Jan. 22, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 42)
      Photocopy. 4 pages. -- Author: Cockburn, Alexander and James Ridgeway.
  - Goals and Directions for Planning in Cleveland., Sept. 1, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    Photocopy. 44 Pages. -- Author: Ramey, Dave.
  - City of Cleveland Planning Commission. An Expanded Electric Power System for the City of Cleveland., Apr. 1, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    Photocopy. 36 Pages.
  - Cleveland City Planning Commission. Fair Share Plan for Cuyahoga County Housing, Jan. 1, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    Photocopy. 14 Pages.
  - A Strategy and Program for the Revitalization of Cleveland's Neighborhood Use of Community Development Block Grant Funds., Feb. 1, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    Photocopy. 6 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman.
    - Cleveland Neighborhoods, Unknown Author. (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - What Gino Baroni is Doing at HUD These Days..., Unknown Author., May 14, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Cleveland City Planning Commission. Solid Waste Collection and Disposal., Mar. 1, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    Photocopy. 54 pages.
  - Cleveland City Planning Commission. Cleveland's Urban Renewal Experience: Implications for the Use of Community Development Revenue Sharing Funds., Dec. 1, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 48)
    Photocopy. 60 pages.
  - Ohio Public Interest Campaign. Cleveland Public Interest Report (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Cleveland Report, 1:1., Dec. 31, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Cleveland Report, 2:1., Feb. 1, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Cleveland Report, 2:2., Mar. 1, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Cleveland Report, 2:3., Apr. 1, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Cleveland Report, 2:4., May/June 1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Cleveland Report, 2:5., Sept./Oct. 1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Cleveland Report, 2:6., Nov. 1, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Public Interest Report, 6:3., May/June 1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Public Interest Report, 6:4., July/Aug. 1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Public Interest Report, 6:5., Sept./Oct. 1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Ohio Public Interest Group. Monthly Report & Others (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Ohio Public Interest Group, Everybody Pays Taxes. Right?, Original Pamphlet, 1 Page (Box 12, Folder 50)
      Original Pamphlet. 1 page.
    - Ohio Public Interest Group, The Ohio Fair Tax Initiative. (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Tax Abatement Will Cost You! (Box 12, Folder 50)
      Original Pamphlet. 1 page. -- Author: Peirpoint, Boyd.
    - "Petitions Filed to Force Tax Relief in Ohio." The Plain Dealer. (Box 12, Folder 50)
      Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Kermisch, Amos.
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Clevelanders for Public Power. We're Turned on to Muny Light. (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. Monthly Report, 2:5., Oct./Nov. 1977 (Box 12, Folder 50)
      2 copies. Original Publication. 4 pages.
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. Public Interest Report, 3:2., Mar./Apr. 1978 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. Public Interest Report, 3:3., May/June 1978 (Box 12, Folder 50)
      3 copies. Original Publication. 4 pages.
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. Public Interest Report, 3:4., July/Aug., 1978 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. Public Interest Report, 3:5., Nov./Dec. 1978 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. Public Interest Report, 4:1., Jan./Feb. 1979 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. Public Interest Report, 4:2., Mar./Apr. 1979 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. Public Interest Report, 4:3., May/June 1979 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Ohio Public Interest Group. Public Interest Report, 4:4., July/Aug. 1979 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Book Outline, Cleveland City Planning, 1970-1980, Feb. 3, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    Photocopy. Approx. 200 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman.
  - "Kucinich Defines Urban Populism." The Cleveland Press., Oct. 3, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 52)
    2 copies. Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Kucinich, Dennis
  - Toward a Work Program For an Advocate Planning Agency, Oct. 1, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    2 copies. Photocopy. 27 pages. -- Author: Krumholz, Norman and Bonner.
  - The People's Caucus of the Cleveland City Council Calls The Council Reduction Move an Attack on The People's Right to Effective Representation and a Move Which Will Strengthen Forbes' Grip Over Council., June 19, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 54)
    Photocopy. 13 pages. -- Author: McFadden, Lester, Barbara Pringle and Jay Westbrook.
    - Documents from Westbrook File. (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Cleveland Project (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Cleveland Bibliography. (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Cleveland Planning Commission. Annual Reports, Capital Improvement Programs and Comprehensive Plans. (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Public Interest Bibliography. (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Some Current (I.E., Within the Last Couple of Weeks) Items of News from the Cleveland Plain Dealer. (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Cleveland News Summary Number Two (Up to June 22nd). (Box 12, Folder 55)
      Photocopies. 5 pages.
    - Cleveland News Summary III., Aug. 17, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 55)
      Photocopies. 7 pages.
    - Cleveland News Summary IV., Sept. 21, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 55)
      Photocopies. 3 pages.
    - Cleveland News Summary VI., Oct. 1, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Cleveland News Summary V., Aug.-Oct. 1979 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Various Cleveland Statistics. (Box 12, Folder 55)
      Photocopies. 13 pages.
    - Cleveland: The Case Study of the Struggles Between The Central City and The Suburbs, Paper for CRP 500., Apr. 15, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 55)
      Original Publication. 5 pages. -- Author: Mekvichai, Banasopit.
    - The Baking of the Cleveland Regional Doughnut. (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - What Gino Baroni is Doing at HUD These Days..., Unknown Author., May 14, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - The New Administration and the Financial Supervision Commission. (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Handwritten Notes. (Box 12, Folder 55)
      Handwritten Note. 1 page.
    - Corporate Control vs. Populism: A Comparative Study of Five Cleveland Mayors. (Box 12, Folder 55)
      Photocopy. 39 Pages.
    - A Historical Analysis of the Cleveland Regional Economy According to Changes in Spatial Structure and Modes of Capital Accumulation. (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Urban Decay and Revival: Contrasts in Cleveland. A Proposal to the Cleveland Foundation., Apr. 29, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 55)
      Photocopy. 16 pages. -- Author: Clavel, Pierre and William W. Goldsmith.
    - Urban Decay and Revival: Contrasts in Cleveland. Grant Application. (Box 12, Folder 55)
      Photocopy. 44 Pages. -- Author: Goldsmith, W.W.
- Series VI: Burlington, Vermont
  - Aswad, William. Burlington Free Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    -- Author:
  - "Connector Would Make Roads Safer for Residents." (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Aswad, William.
  - "Connector: Let's Get on With It." p. 8A., Feb. 2, 1984. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Bates, Beth. Articles. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "Left Cultivates Arts Flowering in Burlington." In These Times., Feb. 23-Mar. 1, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Bates, Beth.
  - "The Arts Explosion." Vermont Vanguard Press. P. 17., May 1-8, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Beauchemin, Joan. Burlington Free Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - "Connector-Type Highways Have Failed to Meet Goal's Drawing People Into Cities. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Beauchemin, Joan.
  - "Southern Connector Takes Wrong Turns." (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Photocopy. 2 page. -- Author: Beauchemin, Joan.
  - "Support Needed for Planning Assemblies to Work Well." (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Beliveau, Armand. Burlington Free Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "Connector, If Built as Designed, May Not Do Anybody Good." (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Beliveau, Armand.
  - "Connector Should Be Halted: parkway Should Be Explored.", Jan. 26, 1984. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Davis, Hamilton. Vermont Vanguard Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "A Lefty Leads with His Right.", May 22-29, 2983 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Davis, Hamilton.
  - "Development Coalition Gives Burlington Area Pipeline to Prospects." (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Sanders Wins the Battle., May 29-June 5, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    2 copies. Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Davis, Hamilton.
  - Donnelly, John. Burlington Free Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Burlington's Men in Blue May Join Best-Paid Ranks." p. 1B, 2B., May 15, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Donnelly, John.
  - "Dreams Flashy, Details Lacking.", Jan. 27, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Neighbors Unite to Help Take Bite Out of Crime.", May 30, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Photocopy. 2 page. -- Author: Donnelly, John.
  - "Permanent Shelter for City's Homeless Under Consideration." p. 1B, 2B., May 26, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Guma, Greg. Burlington Free Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "Another 'Fluke' Election in City Provided a Historic Precedent for Sanders' Mayoral Victory." (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Guma, Greg.
  - "Complex Political Systems Badly Need an Overhaul.", May 31, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "Participatory Democracy--Do Voters Want Less?", Mar. 19, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Photocopy. 2 page. -- Author: Guma, Greg.
  - "Progressives Win Battle of Burlington." (Box 7, Folder 24)
    2 copies. Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Guma, Greg.
  - "Southern Connector Would Do More Harm than Good." (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Photocopy. 4 page. -- Author: Guma, Greg.
  - Hockert-Lotz, Nelson. Vermont Vanguard Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - "Interest in Waterfront Property Developing." p. 5., Apr. 24-May 1, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Hockert-Lotz, Nelson.
  - "Sartelle's Committee Solution.", May 1-8, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - MacKay, Scott. Burlington Free Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Loan Fund to Sweeten Bid for Development in City.", May 29, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: MacKay, Scott.
  - "Mayor Sanders Eyes $500,000 for Street Work." (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Mayor To Continue in Sam Vein.", Mar. 20, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Photocopy. 2 page. -- Author: MacKay, Scott.
  - "Mayor Wants Developer's Grievance Withdrawn.", May 24, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Panel Approves City Development Office.", Apr. 4, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Residents Describe Waterfront Desire.", Apr. 16, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Right-of-Way Fees Face Legal Battles.", Mar. 16, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Sanders is Victor: All Top City Aides Are Reappointed.", June 7, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Sanders: Worker's Must Stand Up and Fight.", May 5, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Southern Connector Road Lead TO Circus Staged by Aldermen.", Apr. 22, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Tax Appeal: Burlington Property Owners Can GO TO City Hall to Protest Assessments.", May 11, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Tenants Shocked by Big Increases IN City Utility Bills." (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Utilities Argue Against Street Rents.", June 2, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Waterfront Sit May be Sold Soon.", Apr. 27, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Aldermen Begin Political Waltz -- Reorganization.", Mar. 21, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Aldermen May Buck Mayor Over Panel Appointments.", Apr. 5, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Aldermen Vote To Fight Telephone Rate Increase.", Apr. 26, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Allen Gear to Wield Aldermanic Gravel.", Apr. 5, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Blowing the Whistle: Project Lets People Sound Out Against Crime.", Apr. 28, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Burlington Aldermen in Scramble for Power Positions.", Apr. 4, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Burlington Gets More Development Money.", Apr. 20, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Burlington Starts Planting Program.", Apr. 20, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "City to Ask PSB to Make Utility Pay for Lobbying.", June 3, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Developer Asking $3.3 Million Cut on Appraisal List.", May 18, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Gear Hands Out Choice Positions to Sanders Allies.", Apr. 28, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Gear Won't Let Mayor Speak About Connector.", Apr. 21, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Gilson Says Leopold is Not Cooperating in Audit Controversy.", Feb. 15, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Housing Rehabilitation Among Suggestions for rant.", June 8, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Mayor to Speak; Sanders Gear Bury the Hatchet.", Apr. 26, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Marks, Alexandra. Burlington Free Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - "The New Class: Cultural Phenomena Emerges; Can It Change Face of Society?", Mar. 27, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Photocopy. 2 page. -- Author: Marks, Alexandra.
  - "Who Are These New Class Folk?" (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Marks, Alexandra.
  - Melven, Don. Burlington Free Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "$100 Million Waterfront Plan Unveiled.", Jan. 27, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    2 copies. Photocopy. 2 page. -- Author: Melven, Don.
  - "Alden Releases Names of Waterfront investors.", Feb. 23, 1984. (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Melven, Don.
  - "Clavelle Wants to Spark Interest In Firewomen.", May 22, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "Preliminary Deal with Alden OK'd.", Feb. 28, 1984. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "Progressives Picked Up Seat ON City Board.", Mar. 7, 1984. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "South Burlington Tangles With Development Issues.", Aug. 16, 1982. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "Waterfront Chairman Chastises Sanders.", Jan. 31, 1984. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Pierce, Neal R. Articles. (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - "Pressuring for Growth Sanity in Cities." (Box 7, Folder 29)
    2 copies. Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Pierce, Neal R.
  - "Will the 'Saved' Cities Mean Suburban Slums?" (Box 7, Folder 29)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Pierce, Neal R.
  - Reilly, John. Burlington Free Press Articles. (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - "IBM' Impact: Computer Giant Makes Mark on County.", Dec. 19, 1982. (Box 7, Folder 30)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Reilly, John.
  - "Three High-Technology Plants Bring Area into Computer Age." (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Misc. News Articles (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Photocopy. 27 page. -- Author:
  - "Community Groups. Conduits to City Hall." Burlington Free Press., Sept. 28, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Abbey, Alan.
  - "Vt. Mayors Offer Revenue-Raising Proposal to House." Burlington Free Press., Feb. 3, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Sline, Deborah.
  - "Schools, City Call A Truce." Burlington Free Press., Feb. 4, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Eley, Rob.
  - "Vermont Is Not Recession Proof." Burlington Free Press, Mar. 20, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Photocopy. 1 page. -- Author: Welch, Peter F.
  - "Prosperity in Few Vermont Counties Do Not Make Recession-Proof State." Burlington Free Press., Apr. 4, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Welch, Peter F.
  - "Mitel Will Close South Burlington Plan." Burlington Free Press., June 1, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Eley, Rob.
  - "Burlington's Big Ideas for Lakefront Stalled." Rutland Herald., Aug. 24, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Photocopy. 2 pages. -- Author: Bookchin, Debbie.